<!-- Copyright (c) 2010 IBM Corporation and others. All rights reserved. 
	This program and the accompanying materials are made available under the 
	terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0 which accompanies this distribution, 
	and is available at http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html Contributors: 
	IBM Corporation - initial API and implementation -->
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../icons/cellclumpedsplitter.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Waehlby Cell Clump Splitter</name>
	<shortDescription></shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
			Waehlby Cell Clump Splitter performs object split and merge by shape on a labeling.
			This may greatly improve quality of a labeling, especially for cell segmentation.
			</p><p>
			If your Image contains a lot of holes, you may want to consider preprocessing the input
			with the "Fill Holes" node or other kinds of hole filling.
			</p><p>
			The method used was mainly inspired by a paper by C. Waehlby, "Combining intensity,
			edge and shape information for 2D and 3D segmentation of cell nuclei in tissue sections", 
			and the method use by CellCognition (cellcognition.org). </p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Distance Merge Threshold">
				Objects closer than this distance threshold (in pixels) will be
				considered candidates for merging. Higher values usually result in
				longer computation times.
			</option>
			<option name="Gauss Size">
				Since this split and merge method performs gaussian convolution in
				it's preprocessing step, you may here enter the size parameter for it.
				Usually higher gauss size leads to less splitting, but longer computation times.
			</option>
			<option name="Size Merge Threshold">
				Objects which contain less pixels than "Size Merge Threshold" will be merged regardless
				of their shape, presuming there is another object close enough. Higher values may slightly
				result in longer computation duration.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="">
			Table containing labeling and image columns. Which will be used can be chosen in the
			"Column Selection" tab.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="">
			Table containing or consiting of the refined labeling. The resulting table can be modified
			over the "Column Selection" tab.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>