<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="LabelToPng.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Labeling to PNG Images</name>

	<shortDescription>
	Combines a labeling and its background image to a PNG image. 
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		Combines a labeling and its background image to a PNG image. The node only processes 2D slices and
		produces a collection of multiple 2D slices if necessary. The resulting image is the same as in the Interactive Segmentation View. In particular bounding boxes, bounding box colors and
		bounding box names are supported.<br></br> (Important: You may want to use a Split Collection Column node subsequently!)
		</intro>

		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Dimension Selection">Select the dimensions which serve as the image
				plane and, if needed, additionally the dimension of the channel</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Image Settings">
			<option name="Transparency of Labels">
			Adjust the label transparency value between 0 and 255 where 255 means the labels are completely opaque. 
			</option>
			<option name="Select a Renderer">
				<ul>
					<li>
						Random Color Labeling Renderer renders the labels with the image as background. The colors for the
						labels are determined from the current runtime color table (i.e. same colors as in opened Interactive Segmentation Views).
					</li>
										<li>
						Bounding Box Renderer renders the bounding boxes of the labels with the image as background.
					</li>
					<li>
						Bounding Box Color Labeling Renderer a combination of the two others.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
			<option name="Select Bounding Box Color">
				Sets to color of the bounding boxes in the rendered images. This has no effect on Interactive
				Segmentation Views at runtime.
			</option>
			<option name="Show Bounding Box Names">
				If set to true the bounding box names are rendered into the image.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Labeling">Labelings and Images</inPort>		
		<outPort index="0" name="PNG Images">PNG Images in Collection Cells</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
