<!-- Copyright (c) 2010 IBM Corporation and others. All rights reserved. 
	This program and the accompanying materials are made available under the 
	terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0 which accompanies this distribution, 
	and is available at http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html Contributors: 
	IBM Corporation - initial API and implementation -->
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="merger.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Merger</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Merges images from different columns to one image
		object.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>Merges images from different columns to one image object as
			follows: the input images are regarded as one single line of pixels
			(depending on the iteration order of each underlying image factory).
			These pixel are added successively to the new image object, filling
			each dimension to the given maximum. If the maximum is reached, the
			next dimensions is added and/or extended.</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Image to merge">Select the columns containing the images to
				merge.
			</option>
			<option name="Result dimensions">
				Specify the maximum pixel number (integer) for the
				first, second,
				third, ... dimension, separated by ',' (comma) (
				<b>NOTE</b>
				: for convenience one can also type there dimension labels, which
				will be replaced by the according dimension from the input image).
				<b>Example:</b>
				If you, e.g., want to merge three 2D source images of width 500 and
				height 400 pixels, than write '500,400' and the 3rd dimension will
				contain the three images. The result image will be of size
				500x400x.. no matter what size the input image has. If you type
				"X,Y" instead, then these labels will be replaced by the actuall
				dimension from the currently processed input image.
			</option>
			<option name="Result dimension names">The labels for the dimensions of the result
				images.</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Additional Settings">
			<option name="Image Factory">Defines the way how the images are created and
				therewith kept in memory: Array Image Factory (stored as ONE array;
				pros: fast pixel access; cons: limited number of pixels per image),
				Planar Image Factory (each plane is stored in an array; pros: images
				are read faster; cons: limited number of pixels in an XY-plane,
				slower pixel access))
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Images">Images</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Merged Images">Merged Images</outPort>
	</ports>

	<views>
		<view name="Table Cell View" index="0"></view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>