<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!-- Copyright (c) 2010 IBM Corporation
	and others. All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
	are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0 which
	accompanies this distribution, and is available at http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
	Contributors: IBM Corporation - initial API and implementation -->

<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<!-- <knimeNode icon="TrackHiliter.png" type="Manipulator"> -->
<knimeNode icon="TrackHiliter.png" type="Visualizer">

	<name>Track HiLite Propagator </name>

	<shortDescription>
		Helper node that enables hiliting of tracks created by the LAPTracker Node.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro> This assistant node for the LAPTracker enables hiliting of all the rows on a track in an interactive view, via different modes. <br/>
		This node's functionality depends on the <b>Attach Original Labels</b> option in the <i>Advanced Settings</i> tab of the <b>LAPTracker</b> Node.
		</intro>
		<tab name="Details">
			<option name="Track Column">The column containing the tracks</option>
			<option name="Hiliting Mode">The way the node handles the Hilitepropagation.
									You can choose between two modes: <b>Track to Points</b> and
									 <b>Points to Points </b> and disabling the Hilite propagation.
									<p> In the <b> Track to Points</b> mode, hiliting a row representing a track,
									 (identified by the <i>Track prefix </i>) in all rows that are on that track to be hilited as well. </p>

									Hiliting <i>any</i>	 row in the <b>Points to Points </b> mode results in all other
									rows on the same track to be also hilited.
									<br/>
									Beware that this mode will lead to undefined results if you attach several LAPTracker nodes to the same
									data source, because the generated rows from differen LAPTracker nodes will have the same rowids and conflict in the hiliting.
			</option>
			<option name="Custom Prefix">The custom prefix for the tracks used by the LAPTracker that generated the tracks.</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Table">Table containing tracks, generated by the LAPTracker node.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Table">The unchanged input Table.</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>
