<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="icons/connectedcompanalysis.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Connected Component Analysis</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Identifies connected components in a image.
  </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				Identifies connected components in a image.
    </p>
			<p>
				Connected component labeling (alternatively connected component analysis)
				is an algorithmic application of graph theory, where subsets of
				connected
				components are uniquely labeled. Connected component labeling is used in
				computer vision to detect connected regions in binary digital
				images.
    </p>
			<p>
				A graph, containing vertices and connecting edges, is constructed
				from
				relevant input data. The vertices contain information required by the
				comparison heuristic, while the edges indicate connected
				'neighbors'.
				An algorithm traverses the graph, labeling the vertices based on the
				connectivity and relative values of their neighbors. Connectivity is
				determined by the medium; image graphs, for example, can be
				4-connected
				or 8-connected.
	</p>
			<p>
				Copied from wikipedia
				<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Connected_Component_Analysis">[1]</a>
				<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pixel_connectivity">[2]</a>
			</p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Connection Type">
				Neighborhood definition.
				<ul>
					<li>FOUR_CONNECTED: These pixels are connected along one of the
						primary axes.</li>
					<li>EIGHT_CONNECTED: These pixels are connected along either one,
						two, or all of the primary axes.</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
			<option name="Background level">
				Background intensity value. Regions of this value are ignored.
				Normally the minimal value of the image type.
    </option>
			<option name="Dimensions">
				The dimension for which the connected component analysis should be
				applied individually. If, for instance, X and Y are selected, the
				CCA will be applied for each XY-plane individually and the connected
				components will have different ID's in the different planes.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Images">Images</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Segments">Labeled segments</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>