<!-- Copyright (c) 2010 IBM Corporation and others. All rights reserved. 
	This program and the accompanying materials are made available under the 
	terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0 which accompanies this distribution, 
	and is available at http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html Contributors: 
	IBM Corporation - initial API and implementation -->
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../icons/peaks.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Maximum Finder</name>
	<shortDescription> Find local maxima on an n-dimensional image. </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				Find pixels with highest value in their local surroundings, so called maxima.
				Output of this node is a binary	image with the found pixels in white (value 1).
				
				When using the option "Output with Tolerance Areas", the output binary image will not
				only contain one highest value pixel in its area, but also all other pixels which have
				the same value (affected by "Noise Tolerance"). Otherwise these pixels positions are
				averaged to one pixel which will be marked in white (value 1).
			</p>
			<p>
				To find minima instead, you might want to invert the input.
			</p>
		</intro>
		
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Noise Tolerance">
				Sets the tolerance for comparison of two pixels. This is useful when an image
				is affected noise or more extreme values between maxima and minima are desirable.
			</option>
			<option name="Suppression">
				Ensures that two maxima are never closer to each other than the suppression value given.
				This is achieved by removing one of two found maxima which do not fulfill this criterion.
				To reduce amount of found maxima, it may be sufficient to raise noise tolerance level instead.
				
				Note: Suppression comes at the cost of a little more computation time.
			</option>	
			<option name="Output with Tolerance Areas">
				If multiple pixels have the same value (respecting noise tolerance) as a maximum they form
				a tolerance area and will be output to the resulting binary image if this option is enabled.
			</option>		
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Image">Input Image</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Maxima Image">Binary image (containing maxima represented as value 1).</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
