<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!-- Copyright (c) 2010 IBM Corporation 
	and others. All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials 
	are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0 which 
	accompanies this distribution, and is available at http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html 
	Contributors: IBM Corporation - initial API and implementation -->

<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="imgreader.png" type="Source">
	<name>Image Reader</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Reads images from possibly different directories and
		imports them to the
		KNIME-internal image format. The images will be
		read an as PlanarImages, which means that they are optimized for the
		access of the first two dimensions. To convert them to another image
		format (ArrayImg if you want to process the whole image at once)
		please make use of
		the converter node.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Reads images from various file formats supported by the Bio-Formats
			library and imports them to the KNIME-internal image format.
			A list of
			the supported formats can be found here:
			<a href="http://loci.wisc.edu/bio-formats/formats">http://loci.wisc.edu/bio-formats/formats</a>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="File browser">
				Choose your image files here and add them to the
				list of selected files.
				An image preview is available which will also
				help you to determine,
				whether an image format is supported or not.
				The list of the core meta data gives you some more information about
				the
				image object.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Additional Options">
			<option name="Append additional OME-XML-metadata column">
				You can add a column containing the metadata formated as
				an
				OME-XML-String
				(more details on
				<a href="http://www.ome-xml.org/">http://www.ome-xml.org/</a>
				).
			</option>
			<option name="Image Factory">Defines the way how the images are created and
				therewith kept in memory: Array Image Factory (stored as ONE array;
				pros: fast pixel access; cons: limited number of pixels per image),
				Planar Image Factory (each plane is stored in an array; pros: images
				are read faster; cons: limited number of pixels in an XY-plane,
				slower pixel access), and Cell Image Factory (multiple arrays of
				fixed sizes are used, pros: unlimited number of pixels per images;
				cons: very slow pixel reading and pixel access))</option>
			<option name="Use complete file path as row key">
				If checked, the complete file path will be used
				as
				row key, else only
				the file name.</option>
			<option name="Check file format for each file">Checks for each file individually the
				file-format, if checked. Else, the file format as assumed to be the
				same for all files and only if the reading fails, the new file
				format will be determined.</option>
			<option name="File name column in optional table">If another node with a string column is plugged
				to the optional in-port, the column, which contains the potential
				file paths, can be selected.</option>
			<option name="Read all series">Some image file formats might contain multiple
				images (called series). One can either read all available series
				(each appended as own table row) or just one series with the specified
				index ("Series index").
			</option>
			<option name="Load group files">If selected, related group files will be read as
				well.</option>

		</tab>
		<tab name="Subset Selection">
			<option name="Image Subset Selection">
				Select the image planes here you actually want to
				open. Use shift or
				ctrl-keys to mark more than one plane or the
				"all"-checkbox to select
				all available planes. Detailed informations
				about the sizes of the
				individual
				dimensions can be obtained from the
				core metadata list above in the file
				chooser.
				The possible dimension
				of
				an image apart from the image width (X) and
				height (Y) are Z (for
				3D-information),
				C (channels, mostly represented by different colors)
				and T
				(the time points e.g. of a video).
			</option>
		</tab>

	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort name="File names (optional)" index="0">Optional input table
			with a column containing the file names/paths.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Images">
			The opened images and optionally a
			column with the metadata.
		</outPort>
	</ports>

	<views>
		<view index="0" name="Table Cell View">
			Displays the selected cells with their
			associated viewer if it exists.
		</view>
	</views>
</knimeNode>